<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title/>
            <author/>
            <editor/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace>
               <location>
                  <geo/>
               </location>
            </pubPlace>
            <date when=""/>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl></bibl>
         </sourceDesc>

      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>This document is part of a larger digital collection of stories of ghost hoaxes from
               the 18th and 19th century London newspapers and periodicals. The project explores the
               beginnings of mass print media in a metropolitan area at a time when technology and
               education made reading common and inexpensive.</p>
         </projectDesc>

      </encodingDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>﻿A Black Ghost on the London and Birmingham Railway

For some time past the policemen and navigators employed on the London and Birmingham railroad, near the central station, at Wolverton, have been dreadfully alarmed by the appearance of a supernatural figure gliding up and down the line, at more than railroad velocity, enveloped in cloud of white smoke instead of steam. This figure,"which resembles a man of colour, is supposed by the superstitious and terrified workmen to be no other than the ghost of a gigantic black, designated Black Shag, and who, about two months since, was buried alive by the falling in of a quantity of earth at a place called Sandy Hole. The body of Black Shag was got out, and buried in Wolverton Churchyard. Since that period his ghost has been extremely troublesome. Sometimes he has appeared to the excavators when engaged at mining any dangerous part of the road, with a huge pair of horns on his head, and as black as soot; and, after capering about in the most mysterious and awful manner, would exclaim, "Take warning by my fate," and immediately vanish. At other times he is seen bearing the resemblance of a tall black, and eliding along the road with amazing velocity, choosing the "witching hour of night’’ for his extraordinary pranks. Several policemen, as well as excavators, have been so terrified by the ghost of “Black Shag,” that they have thrown up their employment; and one man lies now in an alarming state of illness at the above village, from the shock he received at seeing this mysterious visitor, who is the talk of the whole neighbourhood.


</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>