<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title/>
            <author/>
            <editor/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace>
               <location>
                  <geo/>
               </location>
            </pubPlace>
            <date when=""/>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl></bibl>
         </sourceDesc>

      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>This document is part of a larger digital collection of stories of ghost hoaxes from
               the 18th and 19th century London newspapers and periodicals. The project explores the
               beginnings of mass print media in a metropolitan area at a time when technology and
               education made reading common and inexpensive.</p>
         </projectDesc>

      </encodingDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>﻿British Periodicals pg. 217
          “Familiar in their Mouths as HOUSEHOLD WORDS."—Shakespeare.
                    HOUSEHOLD WORDS.
                    A WEEKLY JOURNAL.
             CONDUCTED BY CHARLES DICKENS.
       N°-139.   SATURDAY, NOVEMBER 20, 1852.
	   Price 2d.
 THE GHOST OF THE COCK LANE GHOST.
  We were recently invited into the company of the Ghost of the Cock Lane Ghost, by an advertisement in the Times Newspaper, in which a demonstrator or showman, Mr. Stone, begged “leave to inform the nobility and gentry that he has just returned from the United States, accompanied by Mrs. M. B. Hayden for the purpose of Demonstrating the wonderful Phenomena known in that country as Spiritual Manifestations, and which have created the most intense excitement in all classes of society—Residence, Twenty-six, Upper Seymour Street, Portman Square. Hours at home, from Eleven to Two and from Four to Six.” So the announcement ran. We had read something of the Rochester Rappers and of the mystery, if it be a mystery, called “spirit knocking” in the sentimental language of America. We resolved to visit Mrs. Hayden, and knock up an acquaintance with the ghosts who meet in her apartments, No. Twenty-six, Upper Seymour Street, Portman Square. We ourselves happened to be out of spirits, therefore perhaps we made a wise resolve.
  Yet had we gone for mirth into such company, we should have fared as ill as he who for a midnight jest entered his father’s sepulchre to sup alone among the dead. If it be true, as the believers in the “spirit knockings” tell us, that the spirits of beloved friends whom we have lost speak to us by a noise of rapping, then our most solemn feelings and our tenderest emotions are awakened by the act of positive communion with the dead.
  If it be otherwise—if that which is the holiest ground within the human heart be through such exhibitions dug into for gold by coarse impostors—if the simple questioner who with trembling nerves believes that she is brought into the presence of an angel mother with whom it is a foretaste of Heaven to converse—if she be played upon by cheats who laugh under their sleeves at her credulity and turn her money in their pockets,—then such cheating is no matter for amusement. That is an impiety and wickedness far exceeding the measure of an ordinary fraud, which
trades upon our solemn love towards the dead—

    “In slight of that forbearance and reserve 
	 Which common human-heartedness inspires,
     And mortal ignorance and frailty claim,
     Upon this sacred ground, if nowhere else.”
	 
   There have often been people impelled, out of the ignorance and coarseness of their natures, to the forging of clumsy tales, in which they themselves, together with the Supreme Being, are the chief actors. Not many weeks ago two cowherd’s children in France—in consequence of information received direct from the Virgin Mary—became accredited by Infallibility itself as new apostles. Not many months ago a girl in Suffolk dealt divine information through the neighbourhood, attesting her inspiration by total abstinence from food. We may read in pamphlets printed centuries ago, how in some parts of Switzerland and France a divine epidemic seized upon the children, how they preached powerfully in their sleep, and were attended at their bedsides by large congregations; or we may read of “the German Lazarus” who delivered a long list of messages from Heaven, and attested his mission by professing that he never slept. This Lazarus was constantly caught napping; hut he explained the fact to his own honour, by stating that his parents were so much distressed by his incessant wakefulness, that he found it necessary to feign sleep occasionally, for the comfort of their minds.
   
   Knocking or Rapping ghosts are no new imposition. In a relation of facts concerning “spirit-knockings” written in an American pamphlet that is now before us, “by J. Robinson,” we are told much, not only of the knockings of the unseen beings, but also of the imitations of evil spirits, which, “resembled scratching produced with the fingernails.” Now, will any keeper of a knocking ghost, or any lady or gentleman who has taken up the trade of communicating between knocking spirits and the gullible portion of the public (which lady or gentleman is called in the trade a Medium), turn to the Annual Register for the year 1762, and read what is there entitled “A summary account of the proceedings in regard to some strange noises [PAGE BREAK]heard the beginning of the year at a house in Cock Lane, West Smithfield.” Having read the said account, let the said ghost-keeper or Medium answer to our catechism on the History of Knockers in a simple way. Q. Who was the first Medium? A. Little Miss Parsons. Q. Who was she? A. The daughter of the clerk of St. Sepulchre’s. Q. How did the spirit-knocking in her case begin? A. Her father, the clerk, had taken as lodgers a gentleman and lady, and in the absence of the gentleman, little Miss Parsons slept with the lady, who was called Miss Fanny. Miss Fanny complained one morning that she and her bedfellow had been disturbed all night by noises. The noises continued, and at length excited much attention, but the lady and gentleman removed into the neighbourhood of Clerkenwell (where Miss Fanny presently died), and then the noise in Parsons’ house was discontinued. Q. You have said that the first Medium was little Miss Parsons; in what way do you connect the story of the Cock Lane Ghost with her, and discover the resemblance that exists between that child and yourself? A. Eighteen months after Miss Fanny left the Parsonses, and in the beginning of the year 1762, the noises recommenced, and it is recorded of little Miss Parsons, that the child, upon certain knockings and scratchings, which seemed to proceed i from beneath her bedstead, was sometimes thrown into violent fits and agitations; and a woman attendant, or the father, Mr. Parsons, put questions to the spirit or ghost, as it was supposed by the credulous to be, and they had also dictated how many knocks should serve for an answer, either in the affirmative or negative. Now this plan, invented by little Miss Parsons, differs in no material respect from my own. Q. What was the object of Miss Parsons and her friends? A. The ghost declared itself to be the ghost of the deceased Miss Fanny, and its business was to accuse the gentleman of having poisoned her by giving to her arsenic in a glass of purl when she was ill of small-pox. Q. Was not that very wicked? A. It was very capitally done. Little Miss Parsons was removed from house to house, but the noises followed her, the ghost protesting that she would follow her wherever she went, and the exhibition was exceedingly attractive; for,as it is said in the Annual Register,“numbers of persons of fortune and character, and several clergymen, assisted at the vagaries of the invisible knocker and scratcher.” Q. Were the pretensions of this girl seriously tested? A. Yes, they were, she was tied up in a hammock with her feet and hands bound apart from one another, but the ghost refused then to make its knockings audible. The spirit had also promised by an affirmative knock, that it would attend three gentlemen into the vault under St. John’s church, and knock in their presence upon the coffin (Miss Fanny’s) wherein lay her body. Q. I think I remember some lines by Churchill on the subject of this expedition to the vault. Can you repeat some of them? A. I can, for I have found them in the Register. They begin “Dark was the night,” and after exactly a hundred lines of exordium by which the expectation of the reader is prepared, they proceed in ten lines more to disclaim all straining after false effect, and then relate in a single couplet the adventure of the descent to the vault:
   
       “Silent all three went in; about All three turn’d silent, and came out.”
	   
   Q. What was the end of the story of the Cock Lane Ghost? A. The condemnation of poor Mr. Parsons to the pillory. Q. May you not conclude from this, that spirit-knocking is unsuited to the genius of this country? A. I do not know. The people pitied Mr. Parsons, and no egg was lifted up against him.
   The Fox family, by whom this ghostly rapping was revived in America not many years ago, were so successful in their venture —retiring very soon upon a little independence —that the spirit trade, as carried on by them, became at once an established business. A ghost in Rhode Island, improving upon the practice of his ancestor in Cock Lane, induced a young woman to give a dose of arsenic to her stepbrother. In Oneida County there sprang up an association of persons who had become, as they said, impressed by the intimacy which was springing up between the world of flesh and the world of spirits. These people, taking the coarse view of things that superstition favours, believed that we were on the point of realising that state of affairs of which we read in Moore’s Loves of the Angels, or in Byron’s Heaven and Earth. “Spirits,” they said, “are beginning to have power to form friendships and connexions with mortals,” and since, as they declared, it would be wicked to form contracts that might interfere with the rights, and defeat the unknown possible desires, of spirits, two hundred men and sixty women—having a few mediums, no doubt, among their number—abolished marriages. Emboldened by the credulity of thousands who believed in the establishment of a direct communication with the spirit world, some blasphemous persons at Auburn, in the State of New York—determined that no dark recess of profanity, out of which gold could be taken, should be left unvisited— published a newspaper, conducted by the Apostles and the Prophets, under the direction of the Lord Supreme! We quote from the prospectus, simply stating that the publication of the newspaper therein announced did really take place, and was, in fact, a very dreary sample of the lucubrations of the Rappers. “This publication,” the prospectus said, “is dictated by spirits out of the flesh, and by them edited, superintended, and controlled. Its object is, the disclosure of truth from Heaven, guiding mankind into[PAGE BREAK]
  open visions of Paradise; open communication with spirits redeemed; and proper and progressive understanding of the Holy Scriptures, and of the merits of Jesus Christ, from whom they originated in inspiration absolute, and of whom they teach, as the only Saviour of a dissevered and bewildered race. The circle of Apostles and Prophets are its conductors from the interior; holding control over its columns, and permitting no article to find place therein unless originated, dictated, or admitted by them; they acting under . the direction of the Lord Supreme. James Congdon, Charles Coventry, Andrew L. Wilson, and Lonson Bush are its publishers and proprietor; they having become, in full confidence of mind, disciples of the Lord, and being present external agents of the circle apostolic and prophetic; acting under the direction, while faithful, as instruments for the distribution of truth.”
  
  The Fox family, of Rochester, U.S., as we have already said, first revived in America the modern variations on the story of the Cock Lane Ghost. When tested fairly by a perfect stranger, their ghosts rapped out nothing but blunders: however, we are not left even to infer the dishonesty of their pretensions; we have clearer evidence, not only of their fraud, but of the way in which they practised it. Mrs. Norman Culver, a relation of these Foxes, assisted in the depredations upon geese, and shared their secret; but was not so much a wonder of a woman as to keep it. She therefore made a formal deposition, certified by two respectable witnesses, at the town of Arcadia, in the province of New York, in which, among other things she said, “I am, by marriage, a relation of the Fox girls; their brother married my husband’s sister. The girls have been a great deal at my house, and for about two years I was a very sincere believer in the rappings; but some things which I saw when I was visiting the girls at Rochester made me suspect that they were deceiving. I resolved to satisfy myself in some way; and some time afterwards I made a proposition to Catherine to assist her in producing the manifestations. I had a cousin visiting me from Michigan, who was going to consult the spirits, and I told Catherine that if he intended to go to Detroit, it would be a great thing for them to convince him. I also told her that if I could do anything to help her, I would do it cheerfully  [damage] I should probably be able to answer ail the questions he would ask, and I would do it if she would show me how to make the raps. She said that as Margaretta was absent, she wanted somebody to help her, and that if I would become a Medium, she would explain it all to me.” Mrs. Culver thus became an accomplice, and after she had assisted a few times in conveying hints that would suffice for the conquest of her sceptical cousin from Detroit, after a brief probation, she was admitted to a full participation in the mysteries.

  We call particular attention to her story. “The raps,” deposed Mrs. Culver, “are produced with the toes. All the toes are used. After nearly a week’s practice, with Catherine showing me how, I could produce them perfectly myself. At first it was very hard work to do it. Catherine told me to warm my feet, or put them in warm water, and it would then be easier work to rap; she said that she had sometimes to warm her feet three or four times in the course of an evening. I found that heating my feet did enable me to rap a great deal easier. I have sometimes produced a hundred and fifty raps in succession. I can rap with all the toes on both feet; it is most difficult to rap with the great toe. Catherine told me how to manage to answer the questions. She said it was generally easy enough to answer right, if the one who asked the questions called the alphabet.” And so forth, the rest of the details of trickery being all clumsy and common-place enough.
  
  This being the substance of our readings in the matter of knocking and rapping spirits, we paid our visit to the London ghosts established in genteel apartments in Upper Seymour Street, Portman Square, very soon after we accidentally saw the advertisement we have set forth.
  
  We were two—Brown and Thompson. We rapped at the door of the house in which the knocker lived, on a cloudy and warm evening in the beginning of this present November, which month began, as all the country knows, with days unusually dull and close. We do not idly talk about the weather, for it has a definite connection with our story. Having inquired whether Mr. Stone was at home, well knowing that he was—for he had advertised himself to be at home at that hour in the evening to all parties who desired an introduction to the world of spirits —and having replied to the question about our names by stating that our calling was “in consequence of an advertisement,” we were conducted to a drawing-room, in which we found that the maid who preceded ns had just lighted the fire. Mr. Stone presently appearing, solemn as became a man who knew his lodgings to he haunted, pointed courteously to the sticks that had begun to crackle in the grate over the lighted paper, and murmured “We have had no fire here: we did not like to light it, for it is so very warm.” Truly no fire was needed, and we have a reason of our own for citing Mr. Stone’s corroboration of the fact.
  
  To Mr. Stone, who “had just returned from the United States” with Mrs. Hayden, for the purpose of demonstrating those wonderful phenomena, which “have created the most intense excitement in all classes or society,” we introduced ourselves by saying that we had called in consequence of an[PAGE BREAK]advertisement; and we sat down before the man who was to bring us to the world of ghosts. 
  “You are aware,” he said, “that I have given a good deal of my attention to electro-biology?” We {were} aware. “I have recently visited America, where great sensation has been made by manifestations from the world of spirits, made by means of a noise, like rapping. You have perhaps heard of the Rappers?” Something; we came there to be informed. “It is very curious,” said Mr.Stone. “I have examined these manifestations with great industry, and I have arrived at the conviction that they are true, that they cannot be explained by human minds, that they really do emanate from the spirit world. The lady whom I have brought with me is decidedly the best Medium I met with, and I, therefore, thought it well that the phenomena should be investigated in this country.” Mr. Stone here pausing and  looking into the fire, we inquired what might be the theory of Mediums? “It is very singular,” said Mr. Stone. “There are some persons in whose sphere the spirits have more power. The grossness of matter commonly repels them, but there are some people whose nervous systems appear to act---you know how delicate the nervous system is---whose nervous systems appear to act as---we can only suppose, of course, we do not profess to account for these things---as conductors, as magnets, so to speak, whose bodies are surrounded by an atmosphere in which the spirits freely move. In the neighbourhood of such a person, spirits manifest themselves. Such a person is a Medium.” “Your Medium sits at the table, and the ghosts rap on it?” we asked. “She must sit near the table,” answered Mr. Stone, “because---we cannot control or account for it---the spirits will not knock beyond her influence. That is the nature and the necessity of the Medium, but sometimes the spirits will perform their promise to follow some person to a distant place and knock.” (The Ghost of Cock Lane, and the descent into the vault, to witness!) “We were demonstrating the other evening at the house of a distinguished gentleman in the country, when a spirit promised to be present to him in his library at a fixed hour. The gentleman listened, and, being very deaf, heard nothing; but, on holding his ear more attentively, he said that he distinctly thought he caught a rapping. It is very curious that the spirits accommodate themselves to deaf people. During the whole of the evening at this gentleman’s, the spirits knocked more loudly than usual.”
  
  “When Mr. Stone had further talked about distinguished patronage, and about the wonders that had been performed, one of us suggested to him, delicately, as unwilling to hurt his feelings by implying too roughly that a man who trembled on the confines of the other world could think of money, that “Of [PAGE BREAK]course we knew that his time was not wholly given to the public---that there was some honorarium,” the reply was prompt. “One guinea each person, or five guineas for a party of ten.” This being understood, we felt our way to the inquiry, which we shaped as well as we could, “When will the performance begin?” The reply being in effect “We take in each party separately,” we signified our desire to be taken in as soon as possible. 
  
  The door into the back drawing-room being then opened, we were introduced to Mr. and Mrs. Hayden, the Medium’s husband, and the Medium. Introduction having been promptly made, we were left---we, Messrs. Brown and Thompson --- in the lady’s hands. She sat opposite to us on one side of the round table, firm as a rock. 
  
  The Medium sat not only opposite to us; but opposite to the fire. It had first occurred to us when we went into that back drawing-room, that the kitchen had come upstairs; there was such an enormous fire in the grate. Though it was so warm out of doors as Mr. Stone remarked, “We did not like to light the fire” in the front drawing-room; in the back room the glowing coals were heaped into a red-hot mountain; and the whole atmosphere was feverish. What did Catherine Fox tell Mrs. Culver? “Catherine told me to warm my feet, or put them in warm water, and it -would then be easier work to rap : she said that she had sometimes to warm her feet three or four times in the course of an evening.”
  
  As we sat in the hot room, with the table between us, opposite to the Medium who sat opposite to the fire, we had begun to ponder upon by-gone people, and to think how we could seize “the vapoury phantoms of futurity” by questioning the ghosts. “Can we call any spirit?”    “You can speak only with spirits in the room; the room is full of spirits, and some one spirit that is present will often go out, if you wish it, to fetch you another with whom you desire to communicate. If you question one who is here, he will knock, or if you wait, some spirit that desires to communicate with one of us wall knock, and call attention to itself.”---“How did you become a Medium?” “I did not know what it meant when I used to hear the spirits rapping about me in my bedroom, and following me wherever I went. They knocked so distinctly that my husband---who heard them also, when I was present---once got up and opened the parlour door, thinking that there was somebody who wanted to come in. Then I found out that they were spirits who desired to speak, and had no other way at present of communicating with us. If you ask them any question, and they answer yes, they rap; and if they answer no, they are silent. If we use letters of the alphabet, and point to them in succession, they will spell out sentences, and in that way tell what they wish.” This was the substance of the account given by the[PAGE BREAK]Medium, who added some examples of the care taken of herself by the spirits, and of a communication of importance made to her that morning by a deceased child; a story told to us already in the next room by Mr. Stone, whose version had, however, in one point, differed materially from the Medium’s.
  
  A large card lay before us on the table, upon which were printed in capitals, row after row, the letters of the alphabet, and in a last row the numerals 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 0. There were also pencils with which we might point, and there was paper upon which we might write down the letters as the spirits I indicated them, and spell out the messages delivered from the other world.
  
  We were quite still. Brown was solemn; Thompson looked into vacancy; the Medium looked down into the table : we were waiting for a communication from any kind ghost who would
  
        “Be as a presence or a motion——one Among the many there.”——(Rap-tap.)
		
  “There is a rapping!” said Mrs. Hayden with an indistinct certainty about the expression of her voice, as though she really fancied that she heard a rapping, but might be in error. “Who knocks?” we desired to know. “The spirit” said Mrs. Hayden, “desires to communicate with one of us.” Then, talking with her mouth near to the table, as though she were about to sip knowledge from spirits in the wood, she asked “Who do you speak to? Is it to me?” (No rapping.) “Is it to this gentleman?” (No rapping.) “Is it to that gentleman.” (Rap-tap.) That gentleman was Mr. Thompson, who was requested to converse with the spirit: it was probably that of a near relative.
  
    Says Thompson, “Are you related to me?”
    Rap-tap.
	
    “What is the relationship between us?”
	
  Thompson is directed to take up the alphabet, begin at A, and point to all the letters in succession. When Thompson points at M there is a rap-tap. M is put down by his friend Brown upon a piece of paper as the first letter of the word, and Thompson travels through the alphabet again till he is stopped at O, which Brown puts down, while Thompson begins again and gets to T, where, being stopped, to save trouble, he says, “Is it Mother?” Rap-tap. Mother; very good.
	
  But Thompson does not laugh, for very dear to his heart is the thought of a mother who has been known to him from early childhood only as an angel. Surely she would speak to her sou, if she had power, though she has been parted from him for so many years. What starlight musings of the boy who thought that guardian angels lived in stars, and looked up at the sky for hours, to dream which was the bright particular star in which his angel dwelt; what yearnings of the youth for a mother’s sympathy and guidance when all passions and affections were astir; what sacred mysteries belonging to the inmost thoughts of a whole life, so far as it has gone, were touched by the assertions that the spirit of the lost mother was first to speak. Truly then, if there were truth in Rapping, and if that spirit had addressed her son, she would have spoken not in vain.
  
  “Have you anything to say to me?” asked Thompson. Rap-tap. “Will you say it?” Then, by the most tedious process of getting each letter in succession knocked out of the card, and with a few mistakes in spelling, which were corrected as they were made, but which consumed time, the spirit rapped out this sentence : “Dear son, I am well pleased to see you. I watch over you and God blesses you.” Satisfactory, no doubt. A kind of sentence that might be regarded by any reasonable person as a sure proof of the ghost’s authenticity. But would she in the next place authenticate her claim to be the mother of Thompson? Would she convince her son by telling him her Christian name? Thompson began the alphabet with an inscrutable face : but the light from the fire and window, although good enough for a ghost, or for a common purpose, was not good for a Medium. The spirit rapped at T (wrong), at I (wrong), at M (wrong); finally made out Timok—truly an odd Christian name for an English lady; and having, in this instance, the curious peculiarity that it did not contain a single letter of the name that should have been communicated. But Timok might be something mystic. The Medium said it was not mystic but mistake, and complained of the bad light. Spirits, perhaps, are forbidden, spectacles. No more must be done until a lamp was lighted.
  
  Then it was again distinctly intimated to the professed spirit of Thompson’s mother, who had sought this conversation, that nothing mystical was wanted, only the Christian name she had before she died— “Went into the spirit world,” said the Medium, “the spirits never talk of death.”—“Before you went into the spirit world. Do you remember what that name was?” Rap-tap. “Will you tell it me?” Rap-tap. “Do so then, now, if you please.” So again came the answer knocked up from the alphabet, this time, E-U-N-I-C-E—of course, ridiculously wrong—but, as Eunice means “a happy victory,” and it might be again said that the spirit was mystical, Thompson said, “We will presume that there may be some hidden meaning.” “Hidden meaning, you think?” said Mrs. Hayden, listlessly, as though the spirits and their sayings were rather affairs of ours, than others. “Shall we try again fox-the real name?”  “No,” said Thompson, “it is not worth while; I will be satisfied with the first letter of it.” It was then most elaborately defined to the ghost, with almost legal periphrasis, what was required, and the ghost by rap-taps declared itself perfectly clear in its mind, and ready to oblige. “So [PAGE BREAK]now for the initial of your Christian name in this world?”——T. “Is that right?” asked the Medium. Thompson said no. “Then we had better try again, there may be some mistake.” The Medium explained the matter in her own way to the table, and trying again, was again quite wrong, and the Medium proposed to try again. Thompson had no doubt, that in not more than twenty-six trials, and, perhaps, in one or two less, the right letter could be hit upon : so declared himself content. He would now be glad if the supposed ghost of his mother would condescend to name the year in which she passed into the spirit world. Did she remember it 1 Rap-tap; Would she tell it? Rap-tap. And what year was it? Figures being now touched on the card instead of letters, there was a tap at one, a tap at eight, a tap at four (wrong, it should have been at two), and a last tap at nine, which the spirit recanted by refusing to ratify the whole number when asked at the end whether it was what she meant. The Medium probably caught a smile on Thompson’s face, and reserved to herself the advantage of another guess; she then settled upon the year 1846, which was by more than twenty years a blunder. Thompson then ceased from his inquiries, and we all proposed to wait and try the powers of another spirit.

  After the usual solemnities, there was a rapid rat-tat-tat-tat. “What does that mean?” asked Brown. The Medium explained that no two spirits have the same rap, and that by familiarity you know the rap of any spirit as distinctly as you know a voice. That spirits rapped according to their temperaments; those of nervous people tapping quickly, of quiet people almost inaudibly, and so on. “Well, who is this?” asked Brown, and it turned out to be a repetition upon Brown of the dull guesses we had just gone through in the case of Thompson. It was the spirit of his mother. (Brown’s mother, he is happy to observe here, is alive and well.) Had this spirit of the dead-and-alive anything to say? Yes. A dead-and-alive ghost was the properest for the occasion. The most interminable game at beggar-my-neighbour is not half So dull and stupid as the knocking out of long and foolish sentences from the A. B. C. D. card of a Rapper. Brown must have been regarded as a suspicious character by the Medium. The ghost of the dead-and-alive, blundering over letters, tapping back; and, leaving, after all, her sentences in a broken down condition, said to Brown, u Be candid; investigate; be careful; for this is-God’s Work, my son.”

  God’s work! 
  
  The spirit then informed Brown by the usual slow process that his mother’s name was Mary; falling into a trap which Brown had laid, possibly by dwelling with the pencil over M and A and R and Y; also that she had been dead six years --- all wrong. 
  
  “I wish,” said Brown, “to ask some questions concerning the future; can the spirits answer them without your knowing what they are?” “If they cannot, they will be speculated again unluckily upon M. That silent,” said the Medium, “sometimes they do so. Try.” —— “As they are questions which I should not like to ask in public. Will they see them written on paper?”
  
  “O yes.”——Brown wrote down very clearly: ‘Shall I soon be married?’ “Will the spirits answer this question?” Rat-tat-tat. “Is Yes the answer?” Rat-tat-tat. ‘How many children shall I have?’ was written next, Brown saying “This is a question that must be answered in numbers. Does the spirit see it?” Rat-tat-tat. “Can it answer me?” Rat-tat-tat. And so the spirit answered by the usual process, “One Hundred and Thirty-Six.” When the 1 was obtained, and then 1 the 3 to go next to it, and then the 6 to go after that, the rapid growth of Brown’s family amused Thompson, and the imminent carrying on of the sum into thousands was prevented by his ill-timed mirth. The production of children by Brown stopped therefore prematurely at the number of one hundred and thirty-six.
  
  The Medium, who always asked whether the answers fitted, and who did not clearly know whether she might not be succeeding vastly, although she evidently felt a little puzzled by the sense that she was not doing so well as might be expected, was now re-assured by the reverent tone in which the too explosive Thompson asked whether the spirit of his sister were in the room. His only sister being in vigorous health, he did not expect her ghost; but it was there, and very prompt to answer him. How long had she been dead? Two years.

  So the dreary labour was continued; but we cannot fatigue our readers with the whole monotony of a sitting that was not enlivened by one happy guess. After two hours in the presence of the Medium and the great fire, we passed into the front drawing-room again, and paid our money. Mr. Stone trusted that we had found the spirits answering satisfactorily. It appeared to us rather probable that they did answer very satisfactorily at a guinea a head. Nevertheless we grumbled not, and listened to the further wonders that he had to tell of spirits that sometimes not only rapped, but moved heavy furniture about. He had seen a large loo table, he said, turned topsy turvy by the spirits. He told us more, and offered us gratuitously  a fresh sitting, if we had not been satisfied with the first. We had seen enough. We asked for printed information, and brought home with us a pamphlet upon Spirit Knocking, which he recommended to our notice. It had the motto on the cover, “Behold, I stand at the door, and knock.” Within the pamphlet [PAGE BREAK]we have since read of a spit that flew up a chimney, of a stirrup-iron that followed a man through a wood, and other miserable nonsense.
  
  Of the use of Holy Scripture in the writings of these people we abstain from saying much. We will give, however, from the pamphlet placed in our hands one example. The writer dwells, among other things, upon the account of Peter’s coming after his delivery from prison and knocking at the door of Mary’s house, when his friends within, who would not at first believe the servant’s tidings that Peter stood at the gate, said afterwards “It is his angel.” “It is evident from this,” argues the Rapper’s pamphlet, “that those who were gathered together praying, thought it possible for an angel to knock,”——we will quote no more of the stuff. This miserable delusion, the ghost of a dead ghost, this clumsiest of all the cheats that ever offered folly to be bolted by the greedy appetite of superstition without even the courtesy of cooking it a little, did for a short time turn the heads of thousands in America. But, even in America—the Land of Promise to the Mormons, and to many other sects of fanatics——the Rappers came at last to he generally understood after Mrs. Culver’s deposition had been published; the “intense excitement in all classes of society” died out; and now this ghost of the Cock Lane Ghost, having been laid a second time, makes a third appearance, more faded than ever, and by advertisement invites “the nobility and gentry” during the present London season, to be present at its manifestations——“God’s work, my son;”——nothing of the Treadmill quality in it.
  
  </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>