<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title/>
            <author/>
            <editor/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace>
               <location>
                  <geo/>
               </location>
            </pubPlace>
            <date when=""/>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl></bibl>
         </sourceDesc>

      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>This document is part of a larger digital collection of stories of ghost hoaxes from
               the 18th and 19th century London newspapers and periodicals. The project explores the
               beginnings of mass print media in a metropolitan area at a time when technology and
               education made reading common and inexpensive.</p>
         </projectDesc>

      </encodingDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>﻿THE HAMPSTEAD GHOST-LEGAL PROCEEDINGS AGAINST THE POLICE.

It will be recollected that about a fortnight since Mr. Sutton, a respectable solicitor residing at Hampstead, was brought to this office in custody of the S division of police, on a charge of having assaulted two of the constables, under the following curious circumstances:— It appeared that a tail figure in a white mantle had been seen to pop its head up night after night from behind Mr. Sutton’s garden wall, to the great consternation of passengers along the road, especially of females. In consequence of this, an application was made to Mr. Aggs, one of the inspectors of the divisions, who proceeded about a quarter past ten at night, to Mr. Sutton’s house, to search for the “ghost,” accompanied by Serjeant Rymer and another constable. Mr. Sutton not being at home, they communicated the errand they had come upon to Mr. Warmsley, Mr. Sutton’s father-in-law, an elderly gentleman, who (as alleged) gave them permission to search the premises. Mr. Aggs then went away, leaving the constables to perform their duty; but while they were beating the bushes with their staves in the garden for the ghost, Mr. Sutton arrived, and was much displeased at their intrusion, and, as alleged, kicked out the lights and assaulted them both, in consequence of which he was taken prisoner to the station house. Mr. Sutton denied that the constables ever had permission to search his place, and asserted that they had assaulted him, and used him so ill that intended to take legal proceedings against them. Mr. Rawlinson, before whom the case was heard, dismissed it, without prejudice to either party, and the matter for the time ended.

Mr. Sutton, in fulfilment of his declaration, a Judge’s warrant against the two constables, who were yesterday apprehended upon it and conveyed before Mr. Justice Littledale, and at the same time Mr. Aggs, the inspector, was served with two notices of action for a trespass—one from Mr. Warmsley, and the other from Mr. Sutton himself.

Mr. Aggs communicated these facts to Mr. Rawlinson, the sitting magistrate, yesterday, and requested his advice upon the subject.

Mr. Rawlinson said that, as far as he was concerned, he had done with the case.

Mr. Aggs then asked if Mr. Sutton could demand notice of bail to be given, as in such a case it would be extremely inconvenient to have the constables from their duty. As they were provided with bail, he hoped they would he immediately liberated.

Mr. Rawlinson told Mr. Aggs that he did not think such notice requisite.</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>