<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title/>
            <author/>
            <editor/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher/>
            <pubPlace>
               <location>
                  <geo/>
               </location>
            </pubPlace>
            <date when=""/>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl></bibl>
         </sourceDesc>

      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>This document is part of a larger digital collection of stories of ghost hoaxes from
               the 18th and 19th century London newspapers and periodicals. The project explores the
               beginnings of mass print media in a metropolitan area at a time when technology and
               education made reading common and inexpensive.</p>
         </projectDesc>

      </encodingDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>﻿Park Ghost

Public Office, Bow-street.

Yesterday George Jones, of Lieut.-Col. Taylor’s Company of Coldstream Guards, whose declaration respecting the Park Ghost we yesterday published, was brought before Sir Richard Ford, to be interrogated respecting the sight he was supposed to have seen. Previous to his examination, Mr. Stafford, the Chief Clerk, endeavoured to find out whether his imagination had received any impressions from reading any dismal story, or if he had; at the time the phantom appeared to him, suffered the story of the Hammersmith Ghost to dwell on his mind, in order, if possible, to ascertain if he had been misled by his fancies. To these questions he answered in the negative. On being asked respecting the strange object he had seen, he solemnly declared, that he was ready at any time to make oatyh to what he had stated, and that he firmly believed he had seen a ghost. He detailed every thing in Court as near as possible to what we yesterday inserted under his own signature.</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>