<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Another Stockwell Ghost Case</title>
            <author/>
            <editor/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>The Leader</publisher>
            <pubPlace>
               <location>
                  <geo/>
               </location>
            </pubPlace>
            <date when="1857-11-21"/>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>"Another Ghost Case." The English Leader, no. 7, 1864. Nineteenth Century Collections Online, tinyurl.galegroup.com/tinyurl/54Tbb1. Accessed 25 July 2017.</bibl>
         </sourceDesc>

      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>This document is part of a larger digital collection of stories of ghost hoaxes from
               the 18th and 19th century London newspapers and periodicals. The project explores the
               beginnings of mass print media in a metropolitan area at a time when technology and
               education made reading common and inexpensive.</p>
         </projectDesc>

      </encodingDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>A case similar to that of the celebrated Stockwell ghost has led to some proceedings at
            the Southwark police-court. A working man named Baker, and his wife and daughter,
            occupied a house in the neighbourhood of London-street, Dockhead, and for some time past
            the man and woman have been alarmed by singular noises occurring in various parts of the
            house, and by the breaking of crockery, glass, &amp;c., which were thrown about without
            any apparent cause. Baker and his wife were greatly scared by these mysteries, and at
            length spoke to a gentleman connected with the District Visiting Society, who instituted
            inquiries and soon found out the truth of the matter. The daughter, a girl of twelve,
            had fallen into bad habits, and, to prevent her wandering about the streets, she was
            confined to the house. She therefore revenged herself by breaking the crockery-ware; to
            effect which unperceived, she fastened thin hairs to the dishes, jugs, and glasses, and
            dexterously jerked them down. She would do this in the presence of her mother, who was
            so much the victim of superstitious fears, that she never perceived the cause of the
            effect. Baker himself, when giving evidence before the magistrate, said, that he and his
            wife had been frightened very much. The girl sullenly admitted what she had done, and
            said she intended to frighten her parents because they wouldn’t let her go out. She was
            sent to the House of Correction for fourteen days.</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
