<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Not Dead, or No Ghost</title>
            <author/>
            <editor/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Weekly Times</publisher>
            <pubPlace>
               <location>
                  <geo/>
               </location>
            </pubPlace>
            <date when="1836-10-16"/>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>"Not Dead, or No Ghost." Weekly Times, 16 Oct. 1836. Nineteenth Century Collections Online, tinyurl.galegroup.com/tinyurl/55AP33. Accessed 29 July 2017.</bibl>
         </sourceDesc>

      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>This document is part of a larger digital collection of stories of ghost hoaxes from
               the 18th and 19th century London newspapers and periodicals. The project explores the
               beginnings of mass print media in a metropolitan area at a time when technology and
               education made reading common and inexpensive.</p>
         </projectDesc>

      </encodingDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>﻿ On Saturday the following extraordinary circumstance was communicated at <placeName ref="#hattongarden">Hatton
            Garden</placeName>:— About six weeks ago a young woman drowned herself in the canal, and the body
            was owned by a Mrs. Edwards, of Nelson’s Passage, Goswell Street, as that of her missing
            sister. After the inquest the deceased was conveyed in a shell to the residence of Mrs.
            Edwards, when the usual preparations were made for the funeral. The whole of the family
            went into mourning and followed the body to the grave, deeply deploring the untimely
            fate of their relative. On Friday, however, as Mrs. Edwards was passing through Goswell
            Street Road, she was almost petrified at beholding what she conceived to be the ghost of
            her deceased sister. She started back, and after staring at the form for a short time,
            she ran off, when the <soCalled>apparation</soCalled> pursued her, calling out. <q>Mary, stop; Mary, stop;</q>
            but this had the effect of increasing her alarm so much, that the poor woman fell down
            in strong hysterics. When she recovered it was soon proved to her that it was no ghost
            but her real and living sister. The mystery was then unravelled, it appearing that Mr.
            Edwards’s sister, had, in consequence of a quarrel with her husband, determined on going
            into the country, and living with him no longer. The clothes of the deceased have been
            forwarded to the police. It has not yet been ascertained who the deceased was.</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
