<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A Black Ghost on the London and Birmingham Railway</title>
            <author/>
            <editor/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>John Bull</publisher>
            <pubPlace>
               <location>
                  <geo/>
               </location>
            </pubPlace>

            <date when="1832-08-04"/>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>"A Black Ghost on the London and Birmingham Railway." John Bull, 4 Nov. 1838, p.
               526. 19th Century UK Periodicals, http://tinyurl.com/yajx2huh. Accessed 1 August
               2017. </bibl>

         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>This document is part of a larger digital collection of stories of ghost hoaxes from
               the 18th and 19th century British newspapers and periodicals. The project explores
               the beginnings of mass print media in metropolitan areas at a time when technology
               and education made reading for pleasure common and inexpensive.</p>
         </projectDesc>

      </encodingDesc>
   </teiHeader>
<text>
   <body>
         <p>
                <title>
                    <rs ref="ghost">A Black Ghost</rs> on the London and Birmingham Railway.</title>—
            For some time past the policemen and navigators employed on the <placeName>London and
               Birmingham railroad, near the central station, at Wolverton</placeName>, have been
            dreadfully alarmed by the appearance of <rs ref="ghost">a supernatural figure</rs> gliding up and down the
            line, at more than railroad velocity, enveloped in cloud of white smoke instead of
            steam. <rs ref="or">This figure, <rs type="appear">which resembles a man of colour</rs>, is supposed by the
               superstitious and terrified workmen to be no other than the ghost of a gigantic
               black, designated <persName ref="#blackshag">Black Shag</persName>,</rs> and who,
            about two months since, was buried alive by the falling in of a quantity of earth at a
            place called <placeName>Sandy Hole</placeName>. The body of <persName ref="#blackshag">Black Shag</persName> was got out, and buried in <placeName ref="#holytrinity">Wolverton Churchyard</placeName>. Since that period his <rs ref="ghost">ghost</rs>
            has been extremely troublesome. Sometimes he has appeared to the excavators when engaged
            at mining any dangerous part of the road, with <rs ref="ghost" type="appear">a huge pair of horns on his head, and as
            black as soot</rs>; and, after capering about in the most mysterious and awful manner, would
            exclaim, <q who="#blackshag">Take warning by my fate,</q> and immediately vanish. <rs type="appear">At other times he is
            seen bearing the resemblance of a tall black, and eliding along the road with amazing
            velocity</rs>, choosing the <soCalled>witching hour of night</soCalled> for his extraordinary
            pranks. Several policemen, as well as excavators, have been so terrified by <rs ref="#blackshag">the ghost of
               <soCalled>Black Shag</soCalled>
                </rs>, that they have thrown up their employment; and one
            man lies now in an alarming state of illness at the above village, from the shock he
            received at seeing this mysterious visitor, who is the talk of the whole
            neighbourhood.</p>
      
   </body>
</text>
</TEI>