<TEI>
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>A Ghost!</title>
                <author/>
                <editor/>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher type="original">Sunderland Herald</publisher>
                <publisher type="reprint">Douglas Jerrold's Weekly Newspaper</publisher>
                <pubPlace>
                    <placeName type="original">Sunderland</placeName>
                    <location>
                        <geo/>
                    </location>
                </pubPlace>
                <pubPlace>
                    <placeName>London</placeName>
                    <location>
                        <geo></geo>
                    </location>
                </pubPlace>
                
                <date when="1847-09-04"/>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>"A Ghost!" Douglas Jerrold's Weekly Newspaper, 4 Sept. 1847, p. 1119. Nineteenth Century Collections Online, tinyurl.galegroup.com/tinyurl/54Rtk8. Accessed 25 July 2017.</bibl>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <projectDesc>
                <p>This document is part of a larger digital collection of stories of ghost hoaxes from
                    the 18th and 19th century British newspapers and periodicals. The project explores
                    the beginnings of mass print media in metropolitan areas at a time when technology
                    and education made reading for pleasure common and inexpensive.</p>
            </projectDesc>
            
        </encodingDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <title>A Ghost!—</title>
        <body><p>The other evening a young lady had occasion to go homewards down one of the lanes
            leading from the Building-hill. The night was moderately dark, and misses head was full
            of <rs ref="ghost">witches, ghosts, worrikows, bogles, and long-beaked indescribables</rs>. At a particular
            point, <rs ref="ghost">she noted a veritable ghost</rs>, and set up such a scream as awakened all the echoes
            in the neighbourhood, and very deaf ones they are, and fainted away.—Several parties,
            deeming murder had been committed, ran to the spot, and found miss prostrate, and the
            cause of her fright —a white ass, mumbling its scanty supper, drawn from the hedge. She
            is not yet convinced that she did not see a spirit, and has been very ill since. If
            young ladies fainted away at the sight of every ass frequenting these lanes, by day as
            well as by night, burnt feathers would be at a premium.—<title type="publisher">Sunderland Herald</title>.</p></body>
    </text>
</TEI>
